JENETH DIESTA

jen6one9@gmail.com | San Diego, CA | 619-829-8984

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/jeneth-diesta GitHub: https://github.com/jen6one9

Portfolio: https://jen6one9.github.io/that-portfolio-v3/

SUMMARY

IT Project Manager experienced in leading complex technology migrations, application upgrades and product launches. Excellent leader with strong ability to bring together stakeholders across the enterprise. Leverages solid team building skills and emphasizes a "servant leader" mindset. Effectively communicates project updates to stakeholders while ensuring the successful execution of project goals. Ready to demonstrate experience as an IT Project Manager to positively influence and inspire others.

SKILLS

Project Management: Agile, Scrum, Kanban, and Waterfall methodologies, offshore/onshore management, stakeholder engagement, project scheduling, business/IT roadmap planning, SIT/UAT defect triage and resolution, IT change management, Command center lead during production go-live. **Tools:** Confluence, Jira, HP Quality Center, MS Project Suite, ServiceNow, Slack, WebEx

EXPERIENCE

IT Project Manager MUFG, San Diego, CA

May 2016 - Present

Responsible for managing multiple concurrent initiatives of medium to high complexity with cross functional enterprise wide impacts. Effectively manages risk associated with projects through proper communication, escalation and mitigation follow through.

Kev Accomplishments:

- Network Segmentation Led the successful digital channels cutover to the Money Movement Zone (MMZ)
- PCI Compliance Managed a critical key bank initiative to one of the smoothest deployments to date
- Ping app migration Brought on as a second IT project manager to to migrate over 70 applications from SiteMinder to the Ping product suite
- Mobile NCR Upgrade Led defect resolution efforts with the dev team, NCR vendor and testing teams to ensure a successful mobile check deposit experience

Senior Systems Analyst MUFG, San Diego, CA

May 2015 - May 2016

Managed the internal development of obfuscated test data for CIT/SIT/UAT testing. Responsible for alignment and creation of component integration test scripts and CIT test execution. *Kev Accomplishments:*

- Project Wishbone Member of the key delivery team who assisted in performing production validations to ensure that implementation was completed to satisfaction
- Trained new team members in backend mainframe systems key functionality and test data creation
- Strong relationship management with stakeholders to effectively communicate and identify operational issues/risks and recommended process improvement strategy to resolve problems and monitor/measure impact

Systems Analyst Associate/Systems Analyst MUFG, San Diego, CA

May 2012 - May 2015

Mainframe and digital channels analyst responsible for CIT testing, defect triage support, and production go-live validation.

Key Accomplishments:

- Bill Pay Upgrade Supported the successful validation and deployment of the bill payment solution.
- Santa Barbara Bank Acquisition Led multiple collaborative working sessions with IT and business stakeholders in preparation for identifying system limitations, risks, issues during testing in preparation for production go-live.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

University of California, San Diego Extension

Coding Bootcamp Certificate
June 2020 - Dec 2020

Certified Scrum Master (CSM)

Scrum Alliance #964825 Oct 2018 - Nov 2022

COBIT5 Certified

ISACA #2000175289 May 2015 - May 2017

San Diego State University

B.A. Public AdministrationSept 1999 - May 2004

VALUE-ADD LEADERSHIP

National Co-Chair for NextGen Leaders ERG (2018-2020)

MUFG, San Diego, CA

March 2018 - March 2020

Regional Co-Chair for NextGen Leaders ERG

MUFG, San Diego, CA

March 2017 - March 2018

VOLUNTEERISM

- Junior Achievement
- St. Paul's Senior Center
- Alzheimer Association
- Surfrider Foundation
- Serving Seniors